# SUHAIB MUTAWAKEL

# Software Engineering Intern UX/UI Designer

#### About me

I have a great passion for **Software Development** and **UI/UX design**. I spent the past two years working and learning about the field of Autonomous Driving. Alongside that, I enjoy creating beautiful **User Interfaces**, **iOS Apps** and providing customers with great **User Experience**. I have won some awards from my UI designs. I love working as part of a team in which I can grow and be able to contribute to building softwares that can change our future.

#### **Skills**

- Communication
- Organization
- Creativity
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Teamplayer

#### **Technical Skills**

- Java
- Swift

- · C
- Python
- · Coding / CSS
- Wordpress / CMS

#### Software

- Photoshop
- After Effects
- Adobe XD
- Premiere
- Illustrator
- TPT, DOORS,MKS

## **Honors & Leadership**

- Distinguished Officer Team PTK May 2017
- Outstanding Student Leader Award HFC April 2017.
- Honors Program Graduate- HFC May 2017
- Phi Theta Kappa Scholarship Recipient-April 2017.
- Council for World Scholarship Recipient- April 2016.



+ (206) 788 -6392

suhaibtareq@gmail.com



suhaibmutawakel.com

github.com/suhaiboon



linkedin.com/in/suhaibmutawakel

#### Education

2017 / 2019 EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY - Ypsilanti, MI

Bachelor of Computer Science - (Expected Dec 2019)

2015 / 2017 HENRY FORD COLLEGE - DEARBORN, MI

**Associate in Computer Information System** 

#### Experience

Jan.2018 - Current

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN**

Bosch USA, Plymouth, MI

- Perform software development and requirements engineering according to the V-model.
- · Worked on redesigning the APA system through MATLAB with 5 other teammates.
- · Create design documentation in both text and model-based formats.
- · Perform reviews for requirements, designs, and implementations.
- Used TPT to generate full coverage testing reports for models and software implementation.

Sep.2017 - Current

#### **FOUNDER**

Qumri Design LLC, Dearborn, MI

- Worked as part of a team of three to deliver great high-quality Websites, Apps, and designs.
- · Worked closely with the team to design beautiful UI Designs and Prototypes.
- Built Apps that are customizable and user-friendly.
- Designed all types of flyer, posters, and advertisements.

Aug.2017 - Dec 2017

#### **WEB SUPPORT CO-OP**

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- Maintained content on HFC websites using the Drupal content management framework
- Created or extend Drupal websites as needed by maintaining content types and views.
- · Developed and maintain documentation for end users.
- · Provided technical support for content editor and owners as needed.

Jan. 2016 - May 2017

## LEADERSHIP AND STUDENTS MENTORSHIP

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- Established a warm, genuine and open relationship that encourages learning
- · Provided advice, guidance, and support
- · Supported students in their academic career
- Introduced mentees to academia (the educational structure, its politics and players).